Register of the Raymond Moley papers, 1902-1971
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1914-1968. (Boxes 221-246)
  Articles, drafts, notes, reviews and speeches, arranged chronologically. See CLEVELAND PERIOD FILE and COLUMBIA PERIOD FILE for speeches and writings in the context of Moley's work there. See also OVERSIZE FILE and SPEECHES, 1932-1960
  - General
    - General (Box 221, Folder 1)
    - Americanization (Folder 2)
    - Book reviews, 1923 and 1924 (Folder 3)
    - Crime. Articles appearing in the New York Times, November 1928-August, 1932
      - List of articles (Folder 4)
      - Printed copies
        - General, some written by Celeste Jedel (Folder 5)
        - "Behind the Graft in Our Cities," April 10, 1932. Holograph, typescript and clipping (Folder 6)
    - Crime and the administration of justice (Folder 7)
    - Information received from Ernest K. Lindley (Folder 8)
    - Information received from John Willis Love (Box 222, Folder 1)
    - Newsweek reprints (Folder 2-3)
    - Poems, quotations and jokes (Folder 4)
  - "The Academic Man in Politics," n.d. Typescript (Folder 5)
  - Address on lawyers and reform, n.d. Typescript (Folder 6)
  - Address on political leadership, n.d. Notes (Folder 7)
  - "Analysis Finds Big Cracks in GOP Civil-Rights Plank," n.d. Printed copy (Folder 8)
  - Articles on the Cleveland Foundation, n.d. Typescript (Folder 9)
  - Article on extortion, n.d. Holograph and typescript (Folder 10)
  - Article on the Grand Jury, n.d. Typescript (Folder 11)
  - Article on Charles F. Murphy, n.d. Typescript (Folder 12)
  - Article on Tammany Hall, n.d. Holograph and typescript (Folder 13)
  - Autobiography, n.d. Typescript
    - Printed version (Box 223)
    - Book I
      - Part I, "Olmstead Falls," Chapters 1-10 (Box 223, Folder 1)
      - Part II, "Cleveland," Chapters 11-20 (Folder 2)
    - Book II
      - Chapters 1-10 (Folder 3)
      - Chapters 11-19 (Folder 4)
      - Chapters 20-24 (Folder 5)
  - "'Bombshell' Anniversary Marks F.D.R. Mistake," n.d. Printed copy (Box 224, Folder 1)
  - "The Dispossessed Reply," by Moley and Rene A. Wormser, n.d. Review of The Dispossessed of 1962, by Daniel Bell. Typescript (Folder 2)
  - Editorial comment on Movietone Criminal Identification by David A. Krosnick, n.d. Printed copy (Folder 3)
  - "Fighting Issue," n.d. Printed copy (Folder 4)
  - "Government in a Changing Age," n.d. Typescript (Folder 5)
  - "The Irrepressible Conflict", Today, n.d. Printed copy (Folder 6)
  - "The Literary Crimewave," The Survey, n.d. Review of The Elements of Crime by Boris Brasol and The Criminal and His Allies by Marcus Kavanagh. Printed copies (Folder 7)
  - "Locke and Montesquieu Compared as to the Separation of Powers," n.d. Typescript (Folder 8)
  - "The Middle Man and the Divorce Court," by Moley and Manuel Levine, n.d. Typescript (Folder 9)
  - "Mixing Politics and Social Work," n.d. Typescript (Folder 10)
  - "The Nixon Tragedy," n.d. Typescript (Folder 11)
  - "Official Corruption, the Public and its Curious Opinions," n.d. Typescript. Includes background materials (Folder 12)
  - The Outline of Government in the United States, revised edition, by Moley, assisted by Helen M. Rocca, 1925. Printed copy (Folder 13)
  - "Private War Against Public Enemies," n.d.
    - Drafts. Holograph and typescript (Folder 14)
    - Background materials (Folder 15)
    - Clippings about Al Capone (Folder 16)
  - "A Prospect for Lively Banking History," n.d. Typescript (Folder 17)
  - "Public Prosecution in England and Canada," n.d. Written by Moley? Typescript (Folder 18)
  - "Public Spirit: The Life of Democracy," n.d. Typescript (Folder 19)
  - Radio broadcast on the National Recovery Administration, n.d. Typescript (Folder 20)
  - Review of William E. Borah, American Problems, A Selection of Speeches and Prophecies, Political Science Quarterly, n.d. Printed copy (Folder 21)
  - Review of Twenty Thousand Years in Sing Sing by Lewis E. Lawes, n.d. Typescript (Folder 22)
  - "Twentieth Century American Politics," n.d. Holograph (Folder 23)
  - "Who Should Judge Presidential Inability?" by Moley and Raymond Moley, Jr., n.d. Typescript (Folder 24)
  - "Justice Through Common Sense: The Conciliation Court," October 31, 1914. See OVERSIZE FILE, Box 274
  - Addresses on domestic issues, ca. 1914-1918 (Folder 25)
  - Addresses on immigration, ca. 1914-1918 (Folder 26)
  - Addresses on war, ca. 1914-1918 (Folder 27)
  - "The Municipal Court of Cleveland," National Municipal Review, July 1916. Notes and printed (Folder 28)
  - "The Middleman in Divorce," December 2, 1916. See OVERSIZE FILE, Box 274
  - Lessons in American Citizenship, 1917. Includes "Cooperative Citizenship: A Teacher's Syllabus". Typescript and printed copy (Box 225, Folder 1)
  - "Representing All the People," December 22, 1917. See OVERSIZE FILE, Box 274
  - "World Meaning of the Election," Cleveland Press, November 2, 1918. Printed copy (Folder 2)
  - Lessons in Democracy, 1919. Clippings, reviews and contract (Folder 3)
  - Study of immigrants' opinions, based on interviews by Joseph Remenyi. Begun in 1919, never completed
    - General
      - General (Folder 4)
      - Clippings (Folder 5)
      - Correspondence (Folder 6)
      - Notes (perhaps by a research assistant named Deak) (Folder 7)
    - Remenyi's papers
      - Compilation of quotations from interviews (Folder 8)
      - Data (Folder 9)
      - Descriptions of individuals (Folder 10)
      - Forms used in the interviews (Folder 11)
      - Memoranda (Folder 12)
    - Moley's interpretations of Remenyi's interviews
      - Notes (Folder 13)
      - Forewords, introductions and explanations (Box 226, Folder 1)
      - Drafts (Folder 2)
    - Partial summary, 1969 (Folder 3)
  - "Reconstruction in Civic Education," Ohio History Teachers' Journal, January 1919. Printed copy (Folder 4)
  - Review of Proceedings of the National Conference of Social Work, 45th Session, 1918 and American Charities, by Amos G. Warner, National Municipal Review, May 1919. Printed copy (Folder 5)
  - An Outline of the Cleveland Crime Survey, 1922. Printed copy (Folder 6)
  - "Civic Bodies and Good Government," Realty Record, July 1923. Printed copy (Folder 7)
  - "Civic Interest and Crime in Cleveland," National Municipal Review, October 1923. Printed copy (Folder 8)
  - "Educational Purposes are Being Transformed," Barnard Bulletin, December 4, 1925. Printed copy (Folder 9)
  - "The Practice of Politics," 1926. Typescript with correspondence, notes and clippings (Folder 10)
  - State Crime Commission: What They Are, How They Should Be Organized, What They Should Do
    - Draft (Folder 11)
    - Second draft of Part V (Folder 12)
    - Printed copy (Folder 13)
  - "Crime Survey Shows How Law Breaks Down," New York Times, March 14, 1926. Printed copy (Folder 14)
  - "Crime and the Law Under the Microscope," interview, April 11, 1926. Typescript (Folder 15)
  - Address about the political education of women, April 15, 1926. Typescript (Folder 16)
  - Review of Criminology and Penology by John Lewis Gillin, April 15, 1926. Typescript (Folder 17)
  - "Some Principals and Methods in Education for Citizenship," California League of Women Voters Bulletin, May 1926. Printed copy (Folder 18)
  - "Crime Commissions and the Crime Problem," Catholic Charities Review, October 1926. Typescript and printed copy (Folder 19)
  - "The East Turns to Democracy," Women's Democratic News, December 1926. Printed copy (Folder 20)
  - Rules and Regulations of Court of General Sessions, Probation Department, County of New York, December 28, 1926. Printed copy (Folder 21)
  - "Some Tendencies in Criminal Law Administration," Political Science Quarterly, 1927. Printed copy (Folder 22)
  - "An Analysis of the Work and Accomplishments of the Crime Commission of New York State," August 1928. Typescript, clippings and legislation (Folder 23)
  - "A Study of Delinquency Problems," International Boys' Work Conference, December 1928. Printed copy (Box 227, Folder 1)
  - Politics and Criminal Prosecution, 1929
    - Reviews and clippings (Folder 2)
    - Working papers
      - General
        - Background materials (Folder 3-4)
        - Drafts (Folder 5)
      - "Pleas - Nolles - Legal Data"
        - Background materials (Folder 6)
        - Drafts (Folder 7)
      - "Pleas - Statistics"
        - Background materials (Folder 8)
        - Drafts (Folder 9)
      - Prosecution
        - Background material
          - General (Folder 10)
          - Prosecution and office organization (Folder 11)
        - Correspondence (Folder 12)
        - Drafts (Folder 13)
  - "Where Crime Begins," April 24, 1929. Typescript (Folder 14)
  - "Survey Tells the Complete Story of Crime in Chicago," New York Evening Post, May 11, 1929. Printed copy (Folder 15)
  - "Inadequacies of Criminal Law Administration," May 14, 1929. Typescript (Folder 16)
  - "How Criminal Justice Works," July 3, 1929. Typescript (Folder 17)
  - "The Sheriff and the Constable," Annals of the American Academy, November 1929. Printed copy (Folder 18)
  - "Research Studies in Criminology," November 20, 1929. Typescript (Folder 19)
  - Book reviews, 1930. Includes reviews of book by Roscoe Pound (Box 228, Folder 1)
  - Our Criminal Courts, 1930. Includes materials used in preparation for Politics and Criminal Prosecution
    - General
      - General. Includes outlines, memoranda and proposals (Folder 2)
      - Background materials. See also individual chapters
        - General (Folder 3-6)
        - Administration of justice (Folder 7)
        - Appeals (Folder 8)
        - Arrest (Box 229, Folder 1)
        - Judges - Selection by the Bar (Folder 2)
        - Judges of the Supreme Court and Appellate Division (Folder 3)
        - Judicial councils (Folder 4)
        - Law enforcement (Folder 5)
        - Parole (Folder 6)
        - Procedure (Folder 7)
        - Psychiatry (Folder 8)
      - Clippings and reviews (Box 230, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence (Folder 2)
      - Drafts. May include drafts of Politics and Criminal Prosecution (Folder 3-5)
    - Foreword and Perspective (Folder 6)
    - Chapter 1, "The Appearance of Justice." Drafts (Folder 7)
    - Chapter 2, "The Grimy Court of the Magistrate"
      - Background materials (Folder 8)
      - Drafts (Folder 9)
    - Chapter 3, "Bail or Gaol"
      - Background materials
        - General (Box 231, Folder 1-2)
        - Clippings (Folder 3)
      - Drafts (Folder 4)
    - Part II, "The Long Day in Court." Draft (Folder 5)
    - Chapter 5, "Machinery"
      - Background materials (Folder 6)
      - Drafts (Folder 7)
    - Chapter 6, "Rules"
      - Background materials
        - General (Box 232, Folder 1)
        - Detroit court (Folder 2)
        - Greenblatt tables (Folder 3)
      - Drafts (Folder 4)
    - Chapter 7, "The Decay of Trial by Jury"
      - Background
        - Judge (Folder 5)
        - Juries (Folder 6-7)
      - Drafts (Box 233, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 8, "The Riddle of Insanity"
      - Background materials (Folder 2)
      - Drafts (Folder 3)
    - Chapter 9, "The Art of Human Relations"
      - Notes (Folder 4)
      - Drafts (Folder 5)
    - Chapter 10, "Trial by the City Desk"
      - Background materials (Folder 6-8)
      - Background materials (Box 234, Folder 1)
      - Drafts (Folder 2)
    - Chapter 11, "Faith in Facts"
      - Background materials. Includes analysis of the Missouri Crime Survey (Folder 3)
      - Drafts (Folder 4)
    - Chapter 12, "Career Men"
      - Background materials (Folder 5)
      - Notes (Folder 6)
      - Drafts (Folder 7)
    - Galley proofs (Folder 8)
  - "Criminal Justice in Transition," Jan. 17, 1930. Notes and typescript (Box 235, Folder 1)
  - Review of Roscoe Pound, Criminal Justice in America, 1930. Typescript (Folder 2)
  - "Politics and Crime," March 22, 1930. Typescript (Folder 3)
  - "Law Enforcement," June 30, 1930. Typescript (Folder 4)
  - Address on administration of justice, July 15, 1930 (Folder 5)
  - Article on rackets, 1931
    - Typescript and notes (Folder 6)
    - Background materials (Folder 7-8)
  - "Faith in Numbers, Faith in Facts, and Faith in Ourselves," June 3, 1931. Typescript (Folder 9)
  - Article on rackets, Oct. 16, 1931. Typescript (Folder 10)
  - Address on the occasion of the dedication of the Bar?, Oct. 16, 1931. Holograph (Folder 11)
  - "The Market for Crime," November 24, 1931. Typescript (Folder 12)
  - Tribunes of the People, 1932. Clippings and reviews (Folder 13)
  - "Law and its Enforcement," April 11, 1932. Typescript (Folder 14)
  - "Back to the Land," 1933. Typescript (Folder 15)
  - Introductory column for Today, 1933. Holograph and typescript (Folder 16)
  - "Recovery but Evolution," Cosmopolitan, 1933. Printed copy (Folder 17)
  - "The Administration of Justice," Moley, editor, in The Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, May 1933. Printed copy (Folder 18)
  - "Government in a Changing Age," May 29, 1933. Holograph, typescript and correspondence (Box 236, Folder 1)
  - Interview, November 5, 1933. Typescript (Folder 2)
  - "A History of the New Deal," November 11, 1933. Review of Ernest K. Lindley, The Roosevelt Revolution. Typescript (Folder 3)
  - Article on the Supreme Court, November 18, 1933. Holograph and typescript (Folder 4)
  - "Political Science in the Service of the State," December 28, 1933. Typescript (Folder 5)
  - "As Thousands Jeer or Every Man a Kingfish," December 30, 1933. Review of Huey P. Long, Every Man a King. Typescript (Folder 6)
  - General, 1934. Articles on crime, some by Moley and Edgar Sisson (Folder 7)
  - "Halt the Nazi Invasion! Why America Must Fight Hitlerism," 1934. Printed copies in various newspaper (Folder 8)
  - Writing on finances, January 12, 1934. Typescript (Folder 9)
  - "The Nation's Reaction to the Budget," January 13, 1934. Clippings, holograph, typescript (Folder 10)
  - "The Case of the Liberals Under Hitlerism," March 7, 1934. Typescript (Folder 11)
  - "The New Dealers," March 31, 1934. Review of "The Unofficial Observer," The New Dealers - The Low Down on the Higher Ups. Typescript (Folder 12)
  - "There Are Three Brain Trusts," April 14, 1934. Holograph and typescript (Folder 13)
  - "The Man Behind the New Deal," April 23, 1934. Typescript (Folder 14)
  - Article on Nazism, American Hebrew and Jewish Tribune, April 27, 1934. Printed copy (Folder 15)
  - Radio speech on Hitlerism, April 29, 1934. Typescript (Folder 16)
  - "The Faith of our Fathers," May 7, 1934. Typescript (Folder 17)
  - "The New Deal and International Relations," May 5, 1934. Radio broadcast by Moley and Norman Thomas. Typescript (Folder 18)
  - "The Wisdom of Youth," May 12, 1934. Typescript (Folder 19)
  - Article on the National Recovery Administration, June 2, 1934. Typescript (Folder 20)
  - Article on crime, June 30, 1934. Typescript (Folder 21)
  - Article on Texas Rangers, July 14, 1934. Typescript (Folder 22)
  - Article on the vacation of General Hugh Johnson from the administration, July 14, 1934. Typescript (Folder 23)
  - "Reconstruction in America," July 15, 1934. Printed copy (Folder 24)
  - Review of Ignazio Silone, Fontamara, October 13, 1934. Typescript (Folder 25)
  - "Liberalism vs. Radicalism," October 20, 1934. Holograph and typescript (Box 237, Folder 1)
  - "Master of Mexico," October 27, 1934. Typescript (Folder 2)
  - Address concerning the functioning of the Roosevelt administration, September 10, 1934. Typescript (Folder 3)
  - "Roosevelt Runs the Rapids," November 10, 1934. Holograph and typescript (Folder 4)
  - "The Goal of Liberalism," December 5, 1934. Background material and typescript (Folder 5)
  - "Your Stake in the Next Congress," December 15, 1934. Typescript (Folder 6)
  - General, 1935 (Folder 7)
  - "Can Women Understand Politics?" Barnard College Alumnae Monthly, January 1935. Printed copy (Folder 8)
  - Address on the 74th Congress, January 18, 1935. Correspondence, holograph and typescript (Folder 9)
  - "Some Thoughts on the American Scene: Our Unfilled Demand for Goods; The Importance of Distribution; Cooperation Must Be Keynote," Premier Rayon Review, February 1935. Printed copy (Folder 10)
  - "American Fireside," February 10, 1935. Radio broadcast. Typescript and holograph (Folder 11)
  - Address on the Roosevelt administration, February 15, 1935. Typescript (Folder 12)
  - "We, the People of the United States," February 23, 1935. Official Bulletin From Automobile Labor Board. Printed copy (Folder 13)
  - Article on the National Recovery Act, March 2, 1935
    - Typescript draft (Folder 14)
    - Background materials (Folder 15)
  - "Do the Movies Teach Crime?" March 11, 1935. Typescript (Folder 16)
  - "The 44 State Legislatures of 1935: Interstate Cooperation in Combatting Crime," April 2, 1935. Radio broadcast. Typescript (Folder 17)
  - "Direct Relief vs. Work Relief," April 9, 1935. Radio broadcast. Background materials and typescript (Folder 18)
  - "Which Way America? (for Democracy)" May 30, 1935. Correspondence and typescript (Folder 19)
  - "Beyond the NRA," May 31, 1935. Typescript (Box 238, Folder 1)
  - "Let Others Take the Risk," November 2, 1935. Typescript (Folder 2)
  - "Means to a Lasting Recovery," Real Estate and Building Management Digest, December, 1935. Printed copy (Folder 3)
  - "Depression Graduates," June 8, 1935. Typescript (Folder 4)
  - "The Agricultural Adjustment Act decision by the Supreme Court," for the North American Newspaper Alliance, Inc., January 10, 1936. Holograph and typescript (Folder 5)
  - "Commonsense-1936 Model," Vital Speeches, April 24, 1936. Printed copy (Folder 6)
  - "Hits, Runs and Errors of the New Deal," Redbook, August, 1936. Holograph, typescript and contract (Folder 7)
  - "Congress Keeps the Faith," September 7, 1936. Typescript (Folder 8)
  - "Regulation: How Much Can Business Stand?" Vital Speeches, October 9, 1936. Printed copy (Folder 9)
  - "Where Do We Go From Here?" Great Lakes Banker, 1937. Printed copy (Folder 10)
  - Addresses on Franklin D. Roosevelt's proposal to reform the Supreme Court, 1937. For more on the proposal, see SPECIAL CORRESPONDENCE (Folder 11)
  - Statement before the Senate Judiciary Committee concerning Franklin D. Roosevelt's proposal for reform of the Supreme Court, March 23, 1937. Typescript (Folder 12)
  - "What is Constitutional Government?" Commerce: Business Voice of the Middle West, April-May, 1937. Correspondence, holograph, typescript, printed copy and press release (Folder 13)
  - "Reorganizing the Supreme Court," April 19, 1937. Typescript, holograph and press release (Folder 14)
  - "Federal Power Policy at the Crossroads," Flash, published by the Employees of the Nebraska Power Co. and Citizens Power and Light Co., May 1937. Printed copy (Folder 15)
  - "The American Constitution is a Charter of Liberty and a Charter of Order," Coast Banker, June 1937. Printed copy (Folder 16)
  - Address on the New New Deal, July 12, 1937. Typescript (Folder 17)
  - "Politics and Crime," an address given throughout January and February 1938. Background materials and correspondence (Folder 18)
  - "The Social Function of Advertising," Public Relations, 1938. Printed copy (Folder 19)
  - "The Case of Government vs. Business et al." January 10, 1938. Supporting materials and typescript (Folder 20)
  - "Is Opportunity Dead in America?" January 18, 1938. Typescript (Box 239, Folder 1)
  - "Where Business and Government Meet," January 19, 1938. Typescript (Folder 2)
  - "The Average Man's Stake in the Constitution," February 11, 1938. Typescript (Folder 3)
  - "The Brain Trust," March 1938. Holograph, typescript and correspondence (Folder 4)
  - Articles on the beer industry, American Brewer, April 1938. Typescript, correspondence and printed copy (Folder 5)
  - "The Faith of a Commentator," for a Newsweek advertisement, April 1938. Holograph and typescript (Folder 6)
  - After Seven Years, 1939. See also OVERSIZE FILE, Box 276, SPECIAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - Clippings and reviews (Folder 7)
    - Chapters 1-7. Includes drafts, correspondence and background material. Chapter 3 edited by Rexford Tugwell (Folder 8-14)
    - Chapters 8-10 (Box 240, Folder 1-3)
    - Correspondence of Franklin D. Roosevelt with Sam Rosenman and another, October, 1941. Photocopies (Folder 4)
  - "Five Years of Roosevelt - and After," The Saturday Evening Post, series, June-September 1939. Printed copies. See also OVERSIZE FILE, Box 276 and SPECIAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - "Mr. Roosevelt Sets His Cap" (Folder 5)
    - "On The Campaign Trapeze: Five Years of Roosevelt and After" (Folder 6)
    - "The Duel with Hoover" (Folder 7)
    - "Wild Swans and Faithful Dogs" (Folder 8)
    - "Bank Crisis, Bullet Crisis - Same Smile" (Folder 9)
    - "Rehearsal for a Fiasco" (Folder 10)
    - "Kings Cannot Err" (Folder 11)
    - "Heaven or Bust" (Folder 12)
    - "There's One Issue...It's Myself" (Folder 13)
    - "Flirting with War" (Folder 14)
    - "A Portrait of F.D.R." (Folder 15)
  - "A Chance to Go to Work," November 18, 1939. Holograph and typescript (Folder 16)
  - Article on the Democratic Party, January 1940. Holograph and typescript (Folder 17)
  - Statement on limiting governmental power, February 19, 1940. Correspondence and typescript (Folder 18)
  - "The Fascinating Story of TNEC's Neglected Record," The Saturday Evening Post, series. Printed copies
    - "The Great Monopoly Mystery," March 30, 1940 (Folder 19)
    - "Business in the Woodshed," April 6, 1940 (Folder 20)
  - "Road to Safety Built by Work and Courage," Philadelphia Inquirer, August 11, 1940. Printed copy (Folder 21)
  - "Habit of Freedom," Canadian Business, January 1942. Printed copy (Folder 22)
  - "Anniversary on the Lakes: The Great Mesabi Range, Opened 50 Years Ago, is Backlog of the War for Iron and Steel," Los Angeles Times, October 10, 1942. Printed copy (Folder 23)
  - "Political Liberty Through Political Parties," January 13, 1945. Typescript (Folder 24)
  - "The Prospect for Lively Banking History," Banking, October 1945. Printed copy (Folder 25)
  - Review of Raymond Swing, In the Name of Sanity, Tomorrow, May 1946. Printed copy (Folder 26)
  - "How to Sell What America Wants," National Federation of Sales Executives, May 19-23, 1946. Printed copy (Folder 27)
  - What Are We Waiting For? December 4, 1946. Pamphlet. Printed copy (Folder 28)
  - "The Tax Foundation After Ten Years," Tax Outlook, December 1947. Printed copy (Folder 29)
  - Twenty-Seven Masters of Politics, 1949
    - General. Includes interviews with Moley about the book (Folder 30)
    - Clippings and reviews (Folder 31)
    - Correspondence after publication (Box 241, Folder 1-2)
  - Address on international relations, April 1949. Printed copy (Folder 3)
  - "Taxation in a Free Economy," May 13, 1949. Speech, Fourth National Textile Seminar, Shawnee-on-Delaware, Pennsylvania. Printed copy (Folder 4)
  - "Youth in Bifocals," Everybody's Digest, November 1949. Printed copy (Folder 5)
  - "Death Sentence for State Government," Reader's Digest, December 1949. Printed copy (Folder 6)
  - Valley Authorities, 1950. Printed copy (Folder 7)
  - "The Liberal Faith: Lost, Strayed and Stolen," May 28, 1950. Speech, Whitman College, Walla Walla, Washington. Printed copy (Folder 8)
  - "Toward the Point of No Return," June 7, 1950. Speech, Forty-ninth annual meeting of the Health and Accident Underwriters Conference. Printed copy (Folder 9)
  - Review of Marguerite Clark, Medicine on the March, 1951. Typescript (Folder 10)
  - "Economic Liberty Limited by Law," 1952. Speech, Institute of Business and Economic Problems, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Printed copy (Folder 11)
  - How to Keep Our Liberty, 1952. See AUDIO-VISUAL FILE for photographs
    - Clippings and reviews (Folder 12)
    - Clippings and reviews (Box 242, Folder 1-2)
    - Printed copy (Folder 3)